Kohei Hiraga (Kohei Ueno)

Senior Software Engineer at LY Corporation / Node.js Core Collaborator

+81 90-4242-2296 / kohei.ueno119@gmail.com / github.com/cola119 / linkedin.com/in/kohei-ueno

As a Senior Software Engineer with five years of experience at LY Corporation, I specialize in developing web applications and the JavaScript SDK for the MINI App platform with a daily active user base of 50 million. My expertise in JavaScript and Web technology is further demonstrated through significant contributions to open-source projects including Node.js and WebKit.

Experience

LY Corporation Senior Software Engineer

Tokyo, Japan April 2023 - Present

- As a tech lead, led a team of 4 Front-End developers and Collaborated with over 15 people (3 project managers, 4 quality assurances, 2 UX designers, and 8 developers from other teams) to build a MINI App platform called LINE Front-End Framework (LIFF) and its authentication infrastructure, which handles 50 million daily active users.
- Led the development of the JavaScript SDK of the LIFF platform, enabling developers to create web apps as a MINI app on the LINE app, a messenger service operated by LY Corporation with over 150 million daily active users. <u>Link to my presentation on LIFF and developer experience</u>.
- Initiated and led the development of devtools and CLI tools for LIFF, which facilitate debugging, automate tasks, and improve app integration, enhancing the overall quality of LIFF apps and fostering a developer community. Link to my talk on DevTools architecture at JSConf JP 2021.

LY Corporation Software Engineer

Tokyo, Japan July 2019 - April 2023

- Participated in a panel discussion about the sustainability of open-source software, providing
 insights from the perspective of a major open-source (Node.js) maintainer. <u>YouTube Link</u>.
- Developed UI components specialized for the LIFF platform using Web Components technology.
- Developed SPA-based web apps for browsers and LIFF using React and Vue.js, optimizing performance for a smooth experience across all devices, including lower-end models.

Node.js Project Core Collaborator

Remote August 2022 - Present

- Submitted over 40 pull requests to implement new features and fix bugs with a particular focus
 on the `node:inspector` module with my interest and expertise in debugging methodology.
- Mentored individuals interested in Node.js and open-source contributions. Facilitated pair
 programming and code review to enable their active contributions and hands-on experience in
 open-source contribution. <u>Link to LINE Open Source Sprint 2023 report LINE Engineering</u>.

WebKit Individual Contributor

Remote September 2023 - Present

• Submitted over 15 patches, primarily focused on the WebVTT area, leading to a substantial improvement in WebVTT API compatibility from 88.98% to 96.61%. Link to my patch list.

Education

Tokyo Institute of Technology Bachelor's degree, Computer Science April 2015 - March 2019

Proficiencies

Languages: Japanese (Native), English (Fluent), JavaScript, TypeScript, C, C++, HTML, CSS